Howard Abbey

+1 (586) 298-2472

hrabbey@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hrabbey

SUMMARY

Technical communication and international interface skills proven through over 16 years in the automotive navigation embedded software industry. Attention to detail and ability to gain insight into customer desires resulting in end product enhancement and long-term partnerships.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AW Technical Center USA

Assistant Manager, Advanced Engineering

2012 - 2019

- Supervise 3 Advanced Engineering and Product Planning members, focused on navigation, geospatial, ADAS and autonomous vehicle market research and product innovations for Japanese headquarters.
- Serve as Scrum Master for international research team of 9, supporting rapid prototype screen-flow and proof
 of concept development for next generation ideas
- Co-develop proof of concepts, rapid prototypes, and future specifications with local Japanese ex-pats and team members in our Japan and Europe offices through weekly or daily teleconferences.
- Contribute to architecture design reviews for improved road traffic detection systems using vehicle GPS probe big data inputs to machine learning models.
- Present production units, prototypes, future options and innovations to current and prospective customers at conferences, exhibitions, and on-site meetings. as well as internally to company directors via unaccompanied trips to Vehicle Information Technology division Japan headquarters.
- Individually represent company at conferences, prospective supplier meetings and in long-term partnerships.

AW Technical Center USA

Program Management Senior Engineer

2005 - 2011

- Retain OEM and Tier 1 (GM and Delphi) partnership and foster desire to continue working together.
- Negotiate and maintain project schedules including deliverables, requirements, and responsibilities.
- Coach coworkers on how best to influence customers and partners to achieve best technical decisions.
- Specify electronic and software interfaces between navigation module and vehicle infotainment radio.
- Convey customer desires by authoring requirements in an understandable way for development team.
- Improve manufacturability and testability while defining new end-user customer focused features.

AW Technical Center USA

Systems Applications Engineer

2002 - 2004

- Coordinate product development and communication as resident engineer and on-site liaison between Delphi and Aisin AW Japan by leading progress and issue tracking meetings.
- Integrate first release hardware of AW navigation module into audio and display components.
- Investigate and debug customer field complaints, manufacturing problems and specification clarification requests.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering dept., Computer Engineering

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Fluent English, with ability to convey technical topics to novices.
- Elementary speaking and reading of Japanese